Marc Llort Maulion



marcllort@outlook.com





+34 674039512



https://github.com/marcllort

Summary

I am a Computer Engineer with two+ years of experience in backend microservices development. During my time at university, I've worked on countless personal projects (check my Github!), which allowed me to realize my strengths and interests.

I've always been a great problem solver (good googler), quick learner, and a technophile obsessed with the latest devices. Now I'm working as a DevOps engineer, and I get to show off all these elements of who I am.

During my time as a software developer, I worked with Java (SpringBoot) and Golang. Other languages and technologies I have experience with are RabbitMQ, MySQL, and Python.

Now, as a DevOps engineer, I get to work every day with Linux, multiple CI/CD providers (Jenkins, BB Pipelines, Gitlab CI/CD), AWS and GCP, Kubernetes, Prometheus/Grafana, Terraform, Nexus, Docker, Bash, and many others.

I'm still adding new technologies and projects to my tech stack every day, with no intention to stop!

Experience

DevOps Engineer

Nuvolar Works

Jan 2021 - Present (8 months +)

After 1,5 years working as a Java Developer/DevOps Engineer for the Scheduling Engine project, I was promoted to the official position, taking care of all the projects of the company (7+ projects, some of them without that many needs)

- Improved security procedures (AWS permissions, Kubernetes Secrets, private environment variables...)
- Implementation of CI/CD pipelines in all the projects (using Gitlab CI/CD, BB pipelines, Bitrise or Jenkins, depending on the project)
- Implementation of monitoring and logging/tracing (using Prometheus, Grafana and Zipkin)
- Introduced Infrastructure as a Code (IaaS, Terraform) in the Scheduling Engine project.
- Implemented a new Staging and Production environment in GKE (with its pipelines and scripts) for the Scheduling Engine project.
- GitOps practices in all the projects.
- Management of the Nexus Registry of the company.
- Created a company instance of Sonar to improve the quality of code across projects.
- Joined AWS accounts, migration of S3 buckets...

Nuvolar Works

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 (7 months)

- Creation of Integration environment for Scheduling Engine project, using Kubernetes (with Helm, Kustomize), deployed in GKE (Google Cloud Platform).
- Implemented automatic deployment to the Integration environment using GitOps (with ArgoCD).

- Configured RabbitMQ for Integration Environment.
- Worked in the creation of a new Java-based (with Spring Boot) microservice.

Associate Backend Software Developer

Nuvolar Works

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Implemented Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery pipelines for the Scheduling Engine project (using BB pipelines).
- Containerized all the microservices of the project (using Docker).
- · Implemented ELK stack for logging and tracing.
- Collaborate in implementing FTL rules in a distributed system, where maintainability, extensibility, correctness and quality code are the main priorities.

Backend Developer Intern

Nuvolar Works

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020 (8 months)

Worked on a new project named Scheduling Engine, a software system that allows users to assign crew to flights while complying with all the legal requirements aviation operators must follow, such as rules regarding flight time limitations (FTL), cumulative duties, days off...

During this time as an intern, I worked as a regular Software Developer, assisted by my senior colleagues, who gave me lots of autonomy after a short time due to my quick adaption to the project and methodology of work.

Education

La Salle BCN

Grado en Ingeniería, Ingeniería informática Sep 2016 - Jul 2021



Cisco Networking Academy

CCNA1 2018 - 2019

Skills

Java • Amazon Web Services • Kubernetes • Continuous Integration • Continuous Delivery • Scripting • Kanban • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Terraform • Microservices